当时我正在巡逻
So there I am on the look out
突然有人用远光灯晃我的后视镜
when out of nowhere these high beams light up my rear view.
然后把我拦了下来
And then they hit me.
说我非法停车！
I'm illegally parked!
又领到罚单了吧？
Another parking ticket?
比那更厉害 一只靴子
Better, the boot.
大大的金属轮胎夹 根本弄不掉
Big metal tyre clamp, impossible to remove.
对头！
Bingo!
不过警方也是在照章办事
So the local police do their thing
我领着他们跑过整整一个街区
and I led them get all the way down the block.
然后一脚踢掉了那只锃亮的靴子 “砰”的一声
That's when I kick out my new shiny shoe and "bang!"
纽约的警察太没面子了
New York's finests soil themselves.
你是了解我的 阿尔茜
You know me, Arcee
想跟我飞过山作对
mess with Cliffjumper...
先看看你那对牛角！
And check at the horns.
可这似乎违背了汽车人守则第一条：
Not sure how that complies with Autobot rule No.1
保持低调
keep a low profile.
怎么说呢？
What can I say?
在这鸟不拉屎的地方搜索能量实在无聊
Patrolling for energon out here in Dullsville gets alone, so.
我都有点想念霸天虎了
Almost makes me miss the Decepticons.
你是来内华达州的贾斯帕玩吗？
Like Jasper Nevada has a party?
这个星球上无论身处何处 我们都是孤立的 小飞
We're alone wherever we travel on this rock, Cliff.
我收到一个信号
I'm getting a signal.
需要后援吗？
Need backup?
就凭我 需要后援吗？
Do I ever need backup?
我刚发现了一大堆能量！
I just found a whole lotta energon!
霸天虎！
Decepticons!
阿尔茜 关于后援的问题…
Arcee, about that backup...
听好了 小子们
Fair warning, boys.
我给你们点颜色看看
I'll put a few dints in ya.
阿尔茜呼叫擎天柱
Arcee to Optimus.
虎子们回来了
The Cons are back.
小飞处境非常危险
Cliff might be knee deep in scrap.
明白
Understood.
救护车 你有飞过山的坐标吗？
Ratchet, do you have Cliffjumper's coordinate?
我已经锁定了他的信号 擎天柱
I'm locked on his signal, Optimus.
但我们的队员分散在不同的时区
But our team is scattered across time zones.
阿尔茜 隔板 大黄蜂
Arcee, Bulkhead, Bumblebee
在基地汇合 准备进入环陆桥
rendezvous back at base and prepare to ground bridge.
喜欢我的角吗？
You want the horns?
让你们吃个够！
You got 'em.
这里的能量已经没用了
The energon is worthless to me now.
红蜘蛛
Scream
久违了
it's been a while.
我说 你的主子呢？
So, where is your master?
少跟我提他！
Never mind him!
我就是自己的主子！
I am my own master!
还有问题吗？
Any more questions?
把它清理干净
Clean that up.
一个未开发的能量矿
An untapped energon deposit.
所剩无几了吧？
What's left of it?
三年来霸天虎的首次行动
The first Decepticon activity in three years.
但愿如此
That we know of.
如果他们真是在寻找能量
If they're scouting for energon
则可能是为他的回归做准备
they maybe preparing for his return.
不
No.
救护车 你能追踪到他的方位吗？
Ratchet, can you track his position?
不！
No!
飞过山的生命信号…刚刚消失了
Cliffjumper's life signal... just went offline.
声波 怎么了？
Soundwave, what is it?
“你是来内华达州的贾斯帕玩吗？”
"Like Jasper Nevada has a party?"
“这个星球上无论身处何处 我们都是孤立的 小飞”
"We're alone wherever we travel on this rock, Cliff."
还有个叫阿尔茜的…
The one called Arcee...
既然他们在明 我们在暗
Why slay just one Autobot
区区一个汽车人怎么可能让我满足呢？
when we still have the advantage of surprise?
飞过山牺牲了
We must not allow our anger over the loss of Cliffjumper
但不应让愤怒干扰我们的判断力
to impair our judgement.
时至今日 地球上只剩下我们五个汽车人了
As of today, only we five Autobots remain on this earth.
我们要铭记塞博特恩的一切回忆
We owe it to ourselves
不仅为了自己 为了纪念塞博特恩
to the memory of Cybertron
为了在各个星系寻找避难所的汽车人
to any Autobots in any galaxy seeking safe harbour
也为了人类
to human kind.
更要为我们失去的战友
And we owe it to the memory of our fallen comrade
而生存下去
to survive.
阿尔茜？
Arcee?
小飞走了 站在这儿哭是不会让他复生的
If Cliff's gone, standing around here soaking won't bring him back.
如果你们没有意见
So unless anyone minds
我想我还是回去保护人类吧
think I'll get back to protecting human kind.
擎天柱 帮助人类只会导致更多的悲剧
Optimus, helping humans will only result in more tragedy.
我明白你的意思
Your opinion is noted.
欢迎光临KO快餐厅 每个肉饼都顶呱呱
Welcome to KO drive-in, where every paddy is knockout.
您想要点什么？
May I take your order?
两份超级套餐 加量薯条
Two super combos, extra fries.
好 2号套餐两份 还要点什么？
Ok, those numeral twos. Anything else?
有 要些建议
Yeah, some advice.
怎么才能得到和你一样风光的工作？
How do I get an awesome job like yours?
您点的是两份“冷笑话”套餐
So that's two "we're not as funny as we think we are" combos
赠一碟“有种就来啊”小菜！
with the side of "bite me"!
你说什么？
Haha...What did you say?
5.59美元 先生 窗口付款
5.59$, sir, at the window.
我…我要赔钱的
I have to pay for that.
虫兄鼠弟
Twins.
休息一下 沙蒂
Take five, Sadie.
嘿 妈妈 我刚下班
Hey, mom, I just got off.
不 我不去舞会了
No, I'm not going to the dance.
经验告诉我 不能太出风头
Experience suggests I should never cut a rug.
除非我真会跳舞
Unless I'm stealing a carpet.
注意安全？
Be careful?
不是吧？
Seriously?
这儿可是贾斯帕
This is Jasper.
我爱死你了
I love you.
哦 我也爱你 妈妈 我得走了
Yeah, I love you, too, mom. I got to run.
你好啊 美人儿
Hello, beautiful.
怎么现在才出现？
Where've you been all my life?
身材真好！
Nice!
KO餐厅的薪水实在不高
It may take a few KO pay checks
但总有一天 我要买辆和你一样的座驾
but I am gonna own a ride like you some day.
你在对你的摩托说话吗？
Are you talking to your motorcycle?
对…我的摩托？
Yea, my motorcycle?
不 我是说
No, I mean
对 对
yes, yes
它…它是我的 但…
it's... it's mine. But...
不 我不是跟它说话…
no, I'm not talking to...
是在跟你说话
Well, to you, I am.
还好吧 塞拉？
How's things, Sierra?
找时间带你去兜兜风如何？
Take you for a spin sometime?
拜托 油嘴滑舌的家伙 该走了！
Come on, smooth operator, wrap it up!
你…知道我的名字？
You... know my name?
我们一起在大教室听讲座
We're in homeroom together.
我叫杰克 杰克・达比
I'm Jack, Jack Darby.
糟了
Scrap.
别放手！
Do not let go!
谁在说话？！
Who said that?!
红蜘蛛指挥官 已发现目标
Commander Starscream, target sighted
有一名人类少年同行
accompanied by a human youth.
把他们两个都干掉！
Destroy them both!
你…是什么？！
What... are you?
我不存在
I don't exist.
如果你嘴巴不严 我一定不会放过你
Tell anyone about me, and I will hunt you down.
糟了！
Scrap!
我根本不认识她！
I don't even know her!
上来！
Hop on!
那帮人为什么开枪打我们？
Why are those guys shooting at us?
没有原因 小鬼
There's no whys, kid
他们也不是人类
and they're no guys.
你的朋友吗？
Friend of yours?
家人
Family.
嗨 妈妈
Hi, mama.
赛车呢
Racing.
就在大街旁边
Right up the street.
好 再玩儿五分钟
K. Just five more minutes.
说了你也不懂
You have no idea.
够了 虎子们！
This ends here, Cons!
他们是什么？
What are they?
会说话的车变的机器人
Talking cars that turn into robots
或者机器人变的车
or the other way around.
这是…为…了…飞过山！
This.... is... for... Cliff!
没关系 真的
No problem. Really.
别碰他们！
Leave him alone!
求你了…
Please...
乌鸦嘴
Bad call.
快跑！快跑！
Come on, come on!
别往后看！
Don't look back!
我们刚才看到什么了？
What did we just see?
不知道 而且我也不太想知道
No idea, and I'm not sure I wanna find out.
谁想干一仗？
Who's ready to rumble?
怎么这么久？
What took you?
堵车
Traffic.
如果不是被人类分了神
And the Cons would have been scrap-metal
那对虎子早就成废铁了
if I hadn't been distracted by the humen.
人类？
Humen?
两个男孩？
Two boys?
第二个可能是无意间看到我们变形的
I guess the second one caught us in action.
我也不知道 当时挺忙的
I don't know, was a little busy at the time.
如果霸天虎想针对我们
If the Decepticons are targeting us
任何被视为与我们同盟的人 都会有生命危险
anyone perceived as our ally will be at grave risk.
拉夫 嘿
Raf, hey.
这样吧
Look, let's just...
我们对外守口如瓶 就当没这回事儿 好吗？
keep it between us and forget anything ever happened, ok?
杰克！
Jack!
噢 又来了！
Oh, not again!
它…想让我们上车
It... wants us to get in.
不 就我一个
No, just me.
你怎知道的？
How do you know that?
它就是这么说的
It said so.
什么？！
What?
你的在那边
Yours is over there.
可…我真的不认为…
Look, I really don't think that...
还好吗？
How's it going?
拉夫？
Raf?
等等！停车！
Wait, stop!
有史以来…最酷的…摩托
Coolest... bike... ever.
寄宿监护人？
Host parents?
无视
Ignore.
放松 我只想跟你谈谈
Relax. I just wanna talk to you.
你和你的新朋友一起谈吗？
Don't you mean you and your new friend?
小鬼 有很多东西你不明白
Kid, there's a lot you don't understand.
不 我…我明白 我明白
No, I... I get it, I get it.
机器人搏击俱乐部的第一条规则就是
The first rule of robot fight club is
不要谈论机器人搏击俱乐部
you don't talk about robot fight club.
你要搞清楚的是
What YOU need to understand is
我不想有一堆会说话的疯车跟着我
that I don't want a bunch of crazy talking vehicles
害我被人追杀
following me around, trying to get me killed.
这样 你叫杰克 是吧？
Look, Jack, is it?
擎天柱要见你\N正是为了你的人身安全考虑
Your personal safety is exactly why Optimus Prime has requested your presence.
擎天啥？
Wait, eh... Optimus who?
你可能有危险
You maybe in danger
因为你是仅有的几个看到我们的人之一
because you are one of the few, one of the only who have ever seen us.
哥们儿 你还等什么？
Dude, what are you waiting for?
去嘛！
Go with!
糟了
Scrap.
我们干嘛连她也带上？
And why exactly are we taking her?
有规定
Rules.
嘿 什么…哇！
Hey, what... whoa!
酷！
Cool...
不是只有两个吗
I thought there were two.
你不知道吗？
Haven't you heard?
人类可以繁殖
Humans multiply.
我叫拉夫
I'm Raf.
我叫神子
I'm Miko.
你叫什么？
Who are you?
隔板
Bulkhead.
你是一辆车？
Are you a car?
我敢说你是卡车 是大脚车！
I bet you're a truck. A monster truck!
你喜欢重金属音乐吗？你多重？
Do you like heavy metal? How much do you weigh?
用破碎锤打过沙包吗？
Ever use a wrecking ball for a punching bag?
如果你们是机器人
So, if you guys are robots
是谁造出你们的？
who made you?
真要命…
Please...
我们是来自塞博特恩星球的自主机械生命体
We are autonomous robotic organisms from the planet Cybertron.
也可以叫我们“汽车人”
Also known as Autobots.
你们为什么来地球？
Why are you here?
保护你们的星球免受霸天虎的侵害
To protect your planet from the Decepticons.
就是昨晚那些想谋杀我们的喽
The jokers who tried to bump us off last night.
好吧…
Okay...
那他们为什么来地球？
Why are they here?
问得好 杰克
A fair question, Jack.
部分原因是\N我们的星球经过千百年的内战
In part, they are here because our planet is uninhabitable
已经不再适合居住
ravaged by centuries of civil war.
你们干嘛要打仗？
Why were you fighting a war?
原因有很多
Foremost
核心问题 是为了我们的世界对于能量的控制权
over control of our world supply of energon
也就是汽车人以及霸天虎的生命能量
the fuel and life blood of all Autobots and Decepticons alike.
战斗非常激烈
The combat was fierce
持续了数个世纪
and endured for centuries.
起初 我和一个可与之称兄道弟的人并肩作战
In the beginning, I fought along side one whom I considered a brother.
但是 战争可以将理想腐化
But in war, ideals can be corrupted.
正是这种腐化
And it was thus
使威震天误入了歧途
that Megatron lost his way.
这是历史考试题吗？
Is there gonna be a quiz?
那个威震天…
So what does Megatron
还有这些事情
or any of this
跟我们有什么关系？
have to do with us?
很久没有关于威震天的任何消息了
Megatron has not been seen or heard from in some time.
但如果他即将东山再起
But if his return is imminent
我恐怕 又要掀起一场腥风血雨
as I fear, it could be catastrophic.
那些信号是从太空深处传来的
Those transmissions are emanating from deep space.
我可不想浪费能量
I would hate to waste the energon
除非你对此十分肯定
unless you're absolutely certain.
那么就锁定信号坐标
Then lock on transmission coordinates
启动太空桥
and activate the space bridge.
霸天虎们！
Decepticons!
我回来了！
I have returned!